Guide to the United Brewery Workers Pennsylvania Council Records, 1938-1983 AIS.1984.12
ULS Archives & Special Collections
United Brewery Workers Pennsylvania Council Records
1938-1983
ULS Archives & Special Collections
International Union of United Brewery, Flour, Cereal, Soft Drink, and Distillery Workers of America. Local 22 (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
AIS.1984.12
1.88 Linear Feet (3 boxes)
The United Brewery Workers Pennsylvania Council was made up of elected representatives from the various local unions of brewery and softdrink workers in Pennsylvania. Chartered on May 11, 1939, its purpose was to further the interest of Brewery and Soft-Drink workers in Pennsylvania. This collection contains records of the council for the years 1938-1977.
History
The Brewery Workers Union was founded in 1886, when the original five local unions from Newark, New York City, Philadelphia, Detroit, and Baltimore met in convention. The result of the convention was the union's membership to the American Federation of Labor(AFL). The Brewers remained with the AFL until the late 1930s when the union joined the nascent Congress of Industrial Organization (CIO).
The United Brewery Workers Pennsylvania Council was made up of elected representatives from the various local unions. Chartered on May 11, 1939, its purpose was to further the interest of Brewery and Soft-Drink workers in Pennsylvania. The Council sent delegates to state CIO and later CIO-AFL conventions, lobbied the state and federal government, and endorsed political candidates.
In 1944, the Council created a six person Shop Committee in an effort to settle disputes within the industry during World War II.
Scope and Content Notes
This collection contains the records of the United Brewery Workers Pennsylvania Council for the years 1938-1983, in four series:
Series I: Administrative, 1939-1973
Series II: CIO and CIO-AFL Conventions, 1937-1974
Series III: Shop Committee Meetings, 1944-1949
Series IV: Oversize Materials
Access Restrictions
No Restrictions.
Acquisition Information
These records were a gift of Robert Carpen, 1984.
Previous Citation
United Brewery Workers Pennsylvania Council Records, 1938-1983, AIS.1984.12, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Records of United Brewery Workers Pennsylvania Council, 1938-1983, UE/Lab 84:12, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh.
Labor; Brewery workers -- Pennsylvania -- Allegheny County; Brewery workers -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Congress of Industrial Organizations (U.S.); Industrial Union Council (U.S.); International Union of United Brewery, Flour, Cereal, Soft Drink, and Distillery Workers of America. Local 22 (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
- Administrative, 1939-1973; I.
  Scope and Content Notes
  This series of papers deal with the administrative functions of the council from 1939-1973. The functions of the council are represented in alcohol legislation, constitution and by-laws, correspondence, and balance books. The contents of the series are ordered alphabetically by subject. Balance book is the name given to a financial ledger.
  - Alcohol Beverage Industry Factbook, 1966-1970 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Alcohol Legislation, 1949-1972 (Box 1, Folder 2-3)
  - Alcohol Legislation, Resolutions, 1952-1963 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Balance Book, 1942-1951 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Balance Book, 1951-1960 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Balance Book, 1960-1969 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Certificates, The 67 Club, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Certificates, Sky Ranch for Boys, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - The CIO News, August 14, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Constitution and By-Laws, 1939, 1947, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Contract Statistics, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1945-1979 (Box 1, Folder 13-17)
  - Correspondence, National Coordination Committee, 1967-1971 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Finance Reports, 1947-1970 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Insurance and Receipts (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Local Option Elections, 1957-1971 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Maps of Pennsylvania Counties, originally bound in Hevenor Handy Book, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Moonshine publication, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Murtha Campaign, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Pamphlets and Brochures, 1940s-1970s (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Photographs, 1940s (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Publications, 1940s-1950s (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Publications, 1950s-1960s (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Reports to the U. S. Department of Labor, 1959-1973 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - The Liquor COntrol System of the Commonwealth: Report to the Governor, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Right to Work Law, 1963-1964 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Governor Shapp News Releases, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Stapleton Campaign, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- CIO and CIO-AFL Conventions, 1937-1974; II.
  Series II contains records pertaining to the council's involvement in union conventions from 1937-1974. The records in this series explain the functions and proceedings of union conventions. Convention credentials are received invitations from council members attending the convention. Proceedings are the loose minutes sheets received at a convention, whereas bound proceedings are produced after the convention for the participating council.
  - Credentials, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 7-8)
  - Minutes, 1950-1972 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Officer Reports, 1948, 1956, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Report of Officers, 1947-1957 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - CIO and CIO-AFL Convention Proceedings, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - CIO and CIO-AFL Convention Proceedings, 1944-1947 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - CIO and CIO-AFL Convention Proceedings, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - CIO and CIO-AFL Convention Proceedings, 1948, 1950, 1951, 1953, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - CIO and CIO-AFL Convention Proceedings, Handouts, 1937-1972 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - CIO Bound Proceedings, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - CIO Bound Proceedings, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - CIO Bound Proceedings, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Pamphlets (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Report of Officers Brochure, 1947-1957 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Resolutions, 1947-1957 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Proposed Resolutions, 1956, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Speaker Addresses, 1956, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - CIO and CIO-AFL Yearbooks, 1947-1948 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - CIO and CIO-AFL Yearbooks, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - CIO and CIO-AFL Yearbooks, 1957, 1959, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Shop Committee Meetings, 1944-1949; III.
  This series contains the records of the Shop Committee, which was created by the council to litigate problems in the industry. Making up the majority of the records are minutes of the hearings held to solve particular issues like theft, favortism, late-pay, and drinking on the job.
  - Minutes, 1944-1949 (Box 3, Folder 6-13)
  - Committee Handouts (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Oversize Materials, IV.
  This material was added to the finding aid in January 2011.
  - Photograph, 25th Convention, I.U. of U. Brewery, Flour, Cereal & Soft Drink Workers of America, 1933; 1. (Map-case 3, Drawer 11)
  - PA Brewery, Soft Drink, and Distillery Workers Council, Silver Jubilee Celebration Certificate, 1963; 2.